Hey, competition is making health insurance
complicated.  As soon as
a health insurance policy launches a new plan
and it says that it is a revolutionary health
insurance plan, following its
example, another company
launches a new plan by adding some more add-ons to it.
And in this race, the third, fourth and fifth companies
launch health insurance policies with new add-ons and new features.
And as of today, there are such health
insurance policies available
in the market which have add-on covers up to Rs 50, 60, 100.
And these add on covers are
enough to confuse you.  I have
seen many customers getting
so entangled in add-on covers that they are
unable to purchase the right health insurance policy
and many customers end up purchasing the wrong health
insurance policy which does
not meet their financial needs.  Keeping all these
things in mind, today I have
made a comparison of two health insurance
plans.  Many viewers called
that the comparison of health insurance plans should be done with those
health insurance plans which are
similar.  So in today's video
I have brought a comparison of ICC LBA's Elevate Plan
with Care Health Insurance Company's Ultimate Care Plan because
both these plans are almost similar.  You
must watch the video till the end and
can also share it with your friends and relatives.  If you have
come to Insurance Seva for the first time,
then subscribe to Insurance Seva and
also press the bell icon.
So let's start today's video with Fux.  A
full health insurance
policy basically comes in handy when you are
in the hospital and that is a crucial
time.  At that time, you do not remember anything about
what all things you compared the health insurance policy on when you purchased it.
Neither do you
remember the features at that time nor do you
remember the premium at that time.  At that time, the only
thing that remains is that this
claim should be settled somehow and the most
important thing is that it should be settled hassle-free.
So let's start
with the fundamentals of the insurance company because it is the
fundamentals that help in settling your claim hassle-free.
So first of all here I will
talk about the Incred Claim Ratio, the
Incred Claim Ratio of ICICI LBR is 82.24
and that of Care Health Insurance is 64.53.
Now let's talk a little about the incurred claim ratio.
Incred Claim Ratio means
how much amount you have paid as claims against the total premium paid.
Ideally,
an ideal incurred
claim ratio is considered to be between 80% and 90%.  And an
Incred Claim Ratio higher than this is not correct
and an Incred Claim Ratio lower than this is also
not correct.  Because if it is less then the
insurance company is
compromising somewhere in your claim
settlement and if it is more then the
insurance company may incur loss.
Talking about solvency ratio, ICC
LB has 2.69 and Care Health Insurance has 1.68.  The
regulatory guideline is for 1.5.   The
network hospitals are 15,000 ICC hospitals and
around 95,000 Care Health Insurance hospitals.   The
reimbursement claim process is online for both the companies.
You can process your claim through the app and through the link.
Now let us talk about
a very important point and that is the
number of complaints in insurance
observers as compared to the number of customers.
So the total number of complaints of ICC
is 841 complaints and these complaints are
according to your data from 2024 to 2025 and they had a total of
4 crore customers in that period.  So this data
is very good and very up to the mark, that is, it is
customer friendly data.  If we
talk about second number, Hum Care Health Insurance,
they had 3836 complaints and
2.55 crore customers.  So here if I
compare fundamentally then ICC LB
comes at number one and we will keep Care Health Insurance at
number two here.  Now let's talk about
some special features which are a
little unique and different in both these insurance companies.
So first of all let us
talk about their similar features.
So ICAMARD has brought Jump
Start.  Whereas Care Health Insurance has
instant cover.
You get cover for some diseases from 31 days.  Such as
BP, sugar, your obesity,
hyperlipidemia, asthma.  These diseases are
covered in the ICC Labcard.  But
in care, he has
also covered PTCA i.e. one stent within a year.
If a stent is placed within a year,
then you
can get its cover from 31 days by taking this instant cover.   The
second is the Power Booster which is within the ICC LB's Elevate
plan.  Power Booster
is a great add-on cover and you should definitely get it.
This beats your inflation.
If you take a policy of ₹1 lakh, then ₹
10 lakh will keep increasing every year for life.
And the same feature is also available in the
Ultimate Care Plan of Aapka Care Health Insurance.
Next is Infinite Care and
there is Unlimited Care i.e. Care
within Health Insurance.  Both these
features are available in both the plans and it is said
that you can claim any amount of unlimited amount once in your lifetime.
Icima
Deliver plan covers 2 hours of hospitalization
which Care Health
Insurance does not.  Unlimited
restoration is available under both plans for the same person and same illness.
Both plans are same.  ICMAD also provides surrogacy and
oocyte cover, which is
not available under Care Health Insurance.  Now let us take a
look at what
is included in Care Health Insurance.  So Care
Health Insurance
covers you even during the grace period with an add-on cover
which ICC LB's Elevate plan does not offer.
Premium Payback After 5 Years For One
Year.  You bought the policy today.  Whatever
premium you pay today will be refunded after 5 years.
If you have not taken any claim in these 5 years.
This feature is not currently available in ICC Lambda.
Loyalty boost is here.  If
you keep the policy claim free for 7 years, then
whatever time you have will be doubled.
I can already tell you the coverage during the grace period.  I have already
told you.  The
waiting period for PED can be reduced here.  You
can do it for one year or two years
except for those diseases which are available in instant cover.  Apart from
this, i.e.
in Care Ultimate Care, you
also get tenure multiplier.  Suppose you have
taken a policy for one, two, three, four or five years, then you will get the
time limit in the same year in which you have
purchased the policy.  You can use it for 5 years at a time.
This is called tenure multiplier.
Let us assume that today you are purchasing a policy of ₹1 lakh by paying a
premium for 5 years,
then you can claim ₹50 lakh
in the first year itself.  So these are the
special features for both the companies.  If I
compare both, then
Care Health Insurance has slightly more features than
Ultimate Care as compared to IC LBR
's Elevate plan, it has slightly less features.
Now let us see
what the basic features of health insurance say.  When we
purchase a health insurance policy, the first thing
we look at is how much sum assured
we want to take.  So, under the Elevate plan,
you have the option of sum assured ranging from ₹5 lakh to unlimited.
And similarly,
in Ultimate Care also
you will get options ranging from Rs 5 lakh to unlimited time.
Unlimited means that you will get any amount of claim under
any circumstances.   The
entry age and policy tenure are also the same.   There is
no entry age limit.
Any person of any age, minimum 18 years, can
buy both the plans.  Policy tenures of 1
year, 2 years, 3 years, 4 years, 5 years
are available in both the policies.  There will be no variants.
In family size Icima Delivert, Two
Adult Three Kit will cover three children but
Ultimate Care
Two Adult Two Kit will cover only two children.  Talking about room rates,
single private AC room
is available under ICMMA Deliver plan.  Which you
can downgrade and upgrade.   The
premium will go up or down.  But
in Ultimate Care it is available for all room categories.  The
next feature is
payment to ICU.  There is
no copayment in either of the policies.  ICU There
is no sublimit on ICCU.  Pre-
hospitalization and post-hospitalization are
important features of a health insurance
policy.  So you have ICC Labard Elevate plans for 90 days and 180 days.   There
is the Ultimate Care Plan for 60 and 90.  This is where ultimate care gets
compromised.  Be it modern
treatment or day care treatment, there will be no
limit or sublimit capping.  E-
Consultation will be available with teleconsultation add-on in the
Elevate plan and
in Ultimate Care you will get unlimited general
physician access.
I have already told you that the restoration is
unlimited, under both the plans, same
person same illness ambulance up to sum
is assured.  No capping has been placed.
You will get air ambulance add-on
in both the plans.  No claim bonus which is
inbuilt, which we
also call cumulative bonus.  So, 20% yearly maximum up
to 100 will go under the Elevate plan and if we
talk about Ultimate Care, then 50% yearly
and maximum up to 100% will go.  Home
care is a domiciliary cover and the normal
waiting period for PED is 36 months across all policies.
So, it is going to be like this in this also.
You will get annual health checkup as an add-on in both the plans.  The list will be on the list
your tests will be covered.
Alternative treatment which we
also call Ayush treatment.  Both policies are covered.
Now talking about maternity,
you can get one maternity cover by taking add-on in Elevate plan.
After 2 years and after one year, your choice is up
to a maximum of ₹1 lakh.  Ultimate Care does
not have this facility.  Consumables are
available as add-ons in both plans.   All
four lists are covered.  Wellness
Program Up to 30% discount can be availed in both the policies by
keeping yourself healthy by following some steps.
OPD add on is available in both the
plans sir.  Both plans of ₹5000 can be
availed with OPD add-on
with all limits.  The option of deductible is
not available in either of the plans.
This is the basic plan and its special
features.  There are also some discounts in both these
plans.  Talking about ICC LB's
Elevate plan, there is a discount on civil score here.
You get a 15% instant
discount.  If your civil
score is going beyond 800 then this
discount will remain with you round the life as long as
your civil score is maintained.  There
is an early renewal discount of
2.5% under your Elevate plan.  Renew your policy 30 days in advance.
You
can avail a discount of 2.5%.  I have already told you about wellness discount.
And
if we talk about Care, there is a welcome discount in Care.  There
are some conditions.
You can get a maximum discount of up to 30% there
and wellness discount
is also available in Ultimate Care.  Now the
final stage of this comparison has come and in the final stage
I talk about premiums
because it is most important to compare premiums.
Because whenever you
buy a health insurance plan, the first thing you will
see is what your budget is.  So here I have calculated the
premium on three ages.
Age of 40 years means there is an age band between 36 to 46,
after that 45, after that 46 and after that 51
is the address of Delhi NCR.  If someone lives in tier-two-tier cities, the
premium is reduced by 10, 12, 15%.
Here
I have taken a cover of ₹25 lakh at the age of 40.  At
least this much cover should be there today
because inflation is increasing.  If we
talk about Delhi NCR, then the expenses inside the hospital range from ₹00 per day to
₹1 lakh per day.  A
cover of ₹5 lakh will
cost ₹33,923 for two adults and two children for a person aged 40 years and above in Delhi NCR.  ICC Labad's Elevate Plan with
Power Booster with Claim Shield i.e.
cover for consumable items and there will be no capping on room rent.  At the
same time, this premium will be
₹4587 at the age of 46 for the same age group
and at the age of 51, the same premium will be
₹58791.
Now if we compare it with Ultimate Care, then
there, a 40 year old Delhi
NCR adult will ask for ₹38928,
that is, the
premium of Ultimate Care is approximately ₹5000 more, but some of
its features are also more and if I talk about
546 for the age of 36, then there also you will have to pay ₹5,000
more.  You will have to pay ₹206
and even at the age of 51, you will have to
pay approximately ₹4000 more.
You will have to pay ₹6187.  There will be some
extra features in it also.  Now let us come to the conclusion,
what does the comparison of these two plans say?  Look,
everyone has their own choices regarding force.  Everyone has their own
requirements
in their health insurance policy.  But according to me the
most important thing is the insurance company.
Insurance companies have fundamentals.
So here I will put ICC LB at number one.
That is, if I talk about comparison of both, then
for myself I will buy Elevate Plan of ICC LBA
because it is a fundamentally
strong company.  Whether you talk about the incurred claim
ratio or the number of complaints.
Even if you compare the premium, you will have to take ICC LB's Elevate plan.
I will get this plan for ₹5,000 less.
But when it comes to features,
you will get a few features, i.e. three-four features more in Ultimate Care.
Like you
get coverage during the grace period.  Here
you will get one year's premium back after 5 years.
After 7 years your policy will double.
However, these features are not that effective
because we are already taking a power booster.
Where your sum assured will keep increasing by 100% every year.
So this is the overall conclusion,
according to me, IC Lamb's Elevate
plan is the winner here.  But still,
according to your needs, see which
plan suits you.
Whatever questions or queries you have related to these two plans,
you can ask them
in the comment box.  Also, if you want, you
can call our customer care.  I will meet
you in my next video.  Also, don't
forget to join my live stream on Sunday.  Thank you so much.  Have a nice day.
Jai Hind Jai